Guide to the The Columbia Forum [Editorial Files]
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
The Columbia Forum [Editorial Files]
1958-1975.
32.5 linear ft (ca. 38,000 items in 78 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0250
4078629
This collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, memoranda, biographical forms, and promotional materials of The Columbia Forum, 1958-1975.
Historical Note
The Columbia Forum ceased publication in 1975.
Scope and Content
Editorial files of THE COLUMBIA FORUM, consisting of correspondence, manuscripts, memoranda, editorial reports, blurb and biographical forms, and promotional materials. These comprise the authors' morgue, organizational materials, Comments and Letters and "Before the House" sections, biographical and anthology files, and files of unpublished articles.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged.
This collection is arranged in three series:
Series I: Cataloged Material
Series II: Morgues, Rejections, Cover Letters
Series III: Organizational Materials
Series IV: Journal Items
Subjects
Arts--Periodicals.; Literature publishing.; Periodicals--Publishing--New York (State)--New York.; Articles.; Biographies.
Acquisition
1975 M-75 Office of The Columbia Forum
Alternate Formats
Pearl S. Buck letter is on microfilm.
Gift of The Columbia Forum, 1975.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 1-78. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
- Series I: Cataloged Material
  - Correspondence (Box C1-C2)
- Series II: Morgues, Rejections, Cover Letters
  - Author's Morgue
    - Abrams, Charles (Box 1)
    - Abramson, Doris (Box 1)
    - Abramson, Harold J. (Box 1)
    - Adams, Mervyn (Box 1)
    - Adams, Robert M. (Box 1)
    - Akmakjian, Hiag (Box 1)
    - Alaya, Flavia (Box 1)
    - Alberti, Rafael (Box 1)
    - Allen Jerry (Box 1)
    - Ames, Russell (Box 1)
    - Appleman, Philip (Box 1)
    - Ashbery, John (Box 1)
    - Auden, W.H. (Box 1)
    - Bacic, Jakov (Box 2)
    - Bailey, Norman A. (Box 2)
    - Barach, Alvan (Box 2)
    - Bard, Robert L. & Lewis Kurlantzick (Box 2)
    - Barnouw, Erik (Box 2)
    - Barnstone, Willis (Box 2)
    - Barr, Donald (Box 2)
    - Barrett, William (Box 3)
    - Barton, Robert D. (Box 3)
    - Barzun, Jacques (Box 3)
    - Barzun - Luening (Box 3)
    - Barzun/Trilling (Box 3)
    - Baum, Joan (Box 3)
    - Baxter, James and Annette (Box 3)
    - Baxter, Annette (Box 3)
    - Beadle, George (Box 3)
    - Becker, James (Box 3)
    - Beeson, Jack (Box 3)
    - Beichman, Arnold (Box 3-4)
    - Bell, Daniel (Box 4)
    - Benoit, Emile (Box 4)
    - Bentley,Eric (Box 4)
    - Berg, Ivar (Box 4)
    - Berger, Richard Barry (Box 5)
    - Berle, Adolf A. (Box 5)
    - Bermel, Albert (Box 5)
    - Bers, Lipman (Box 5)
    - Bieber, M. (Box 5)
    - Birch, Herbert G. (Box 5)
    - Birdsall, Richard (Box 5)
    - Blau, Joseph (Box 5)
    - Bogin, George (Box 5)
    - Boorman, Howard (Box 5)
    - Booth, Philip (Box 5)
    - Borges Seminar (Box 5)
    - Borges, Jorge Luis (Box 5)
    - Braudy, Leo (Box 5)
    - Brennan, Joseph Gerard (Box 5)
    - Breslow, Paul E. (Box 5)
    - Brody, Benjamin (Box 5)
    - Bronowski, Jacob (Box 5)
    - Brownstein, Rachel Mayer (Box 6)
    - Brustein, Robert (Box 6)
    - Brzezinski, Zbigniew K. (Box 6)
    - Brzezinski, Zbigniew & Samuel P. Huntington (Box 6)
    - Buck, Pearl S. (Box 6)
    - Burns, Gerals E. (Box 6)
    - Byers, Paul (Box 6)
    - Cane, Melville (Box 6)
    - Caplow, Theodore (Box 6)
    - Carter, Paul A. (Box 7)
    - Cartey, Wilfrid (Box 7)
    - Cassin, René (Box 7)
    - Ceravolo, Joseph (Box 7)
    - Chabrowe, Leonard (Box 7)
    - Chargaff, Erwin (Box 7)
    - Chase, Richard (Box 7)
    - Chernush, Akosh (Box 7)
    - Chomsky, Noam (Box 7)
    - Claire, William F. (Box 7)
    - Clements, Robert J. (Box 7)
    - Clubb, Edmund S. (Box 7)
    - Coleman, Samuel (Box 7)
    - Collins, Glenn (Box 7)
    - Commoner, Barry (Box 7)
    - Cooney, Thomas (Box 7)
    - Cort, David (Box 8)
    - Coughlin, Margaret (Box 8)
    - Cox Report (Box 8)
    - Crist, Judith (Box 8)
    - Crossett, John (Box 8)
    - Dabney, Lewis (Box 8)
    - Dallin, Alexander (Box 8)
    - Dankleff, Richard (Box 8)
    - Danto, Arthur (Box 8)
    - Davis, Curtis Carroll (Box 8)
    - Davia, Eunice (Box 8)
    - Davis, Howard McP. (Box 8)
    - Davis, Robert Gorham (Box 8-9)
    - Davis Exchange (Box 9)
    - Day, Charter (Box 9)
    - Day, Lincoln (Box 9)
    - Deane, Herbert (Box 9)
    - De Bary, Theodore (Box 9)
    - De Bary, William Theodore (Box 9)
    - Deutsch, Babette (Box 9)
    - Devons, Samuel (Box 9)
    - Diamond, Stanley (Box 9)
    - Dillon, Wilton (Box 9-10)
    - Dobzhansky, Theodosius (Box 10)
    - Dorozynski, Alexander (Box 10)
    - Dorsen, Norman (Box 10)
    - Dorsen & Rudovsky (Box 10)
    - Douglas, William O. (Box 10)
    - Draper, Samuel (Box 10)
    - Driver, Tom F. (Box 10)
    - Duberman, Martin (Box 10)
    - DuBoiS, W. E. B. (Box 10)
    - Dubos, Bené (Box 10)
    - Dugan, Alan (Box 10)
    - Dunn, Ethel (Box 11)
    - Dunn, Ethel & Stephen Dunn (Box 11)
    - Dunn, Stephen (Box 11)
    - Dworkin, Martin (Box 11)
    - Ebel, Henry (Box 11)
    - Eble, Kenneth (Box 11)
    - Eckert, W.J. (Box 11)
    - Einbinder, Harvey (Box 11)
    - Eliot, Thomas D. (Box 11)
    - Eliot, T.S. (Box 11)
    - Elman, Richard (Box 12)
    - Engel, Leonard (Box 12)
    - Engelbourg, Saul (Box 12)
    - Etzioni, Amitai (Box 12)
    - Everett, Charles (Box 12)
    - Ewing, Maurice (Box 12)
    - Farer, Tom J. (Box 13)
    - Feinstein, Herbert (Box 13)
    - Feldman, Alan (Box 13)
    - Feldman, Irving (Box 13)
    - Feldman, Leonard (Box 13)
    - Felix, David (Box 13)
    - Fels, William (Box 13)
    - Fenner, James L. (Box 13)
    - Ferry, W.H. (Box 13)
    - Field, Andrew (Box 13)
    - Fischer, Louis (Box 13)
    - Fitch, James M. (Box 13-14)
    - Fitch, Robert E. (Box 14)
    - Fjelde, Rolf (Box 14)
    - Flory, Sheldon (Box 14)
    - Fogel, Aaron (Box 14)
    - Fogelson, Robert (Box 14)
    - Fox, Renée C. (Box 14)
    - Frankel, Charles (Box 14)
    - Frankel, Max (Box 14)
    - Freundlich, Lawrence S. (Box 14)
    - Fried, Morton H. (Box 14)
    - Friedman, Peter (Box 14)
    - Friedmann, Wolfgang (Box 15)
    - Frocmkin, Joseph N. (Box 15)
    - Furse, Margaret Lewis (Box 15)
    - Fussell, Paul (Box 15)
    - Gans, Herbert J. (Box 15)
    - Gans-Nisbet (Box 15)
    - Gavronsky, Serge (Box 15)
    - Gay, Peter (Box 15)
    - Gaylin, Willard M. (Box 15-16)
    - Gellhorn, Walter (Box 16)
    - Gilson, Estelle (Box 16)
    - Ginzberg, Eli (Box 16)
    - Ginsberg and Laughlin (Box 16)
    - Giroux, Robert (Box 16)
    - Glasser (Box 16)
    - Goode, Erich (Box 17)
    - Goodman, Paul (Box 17)
    - Goodman, Percival (Box 17)
    - Goodman, Gummere- (Box 17)
    - Goodman, Randolph (Box 17)
    - Goldman, Michael (Box 17)
    - Goldman, Richard Franko (Box 17)
    - Gordon, Jesse and Victor H. Bernstein (Box 17)
    - Gordon, Max (Box 17)
    - Gove, Philip (Box 17)
    - Grant, Louis T. (Box 17)
    - Grean, Stanley (Box 17)
    - Greenberg, Daniel (Box 18)
    - Greenberg-Gershenson Papers (Box 18)
    - Gruliow, Leo (Box 18)
    - Hacker, Marilyn (Box 18)
    - Hadas, Moses (Box 18)
    - Haimson, Leopold (Box 18)
    - Halford, Ralph (Box 18)
    - Halford Dialogue (Box 18)
    - Hall, Robert E. (Box 18)
    - Hamalian, Leo (Box 18)
    - Hamilton, Charles V. (Box 18)
    - Harding, Vincent (Box 19)
    - Haskell, Molly (Box 19)
    - Hawes, Gene (Box 19)
    - Heal, Edith (Box 19)
    - Heilbrun, Carolyn (Mrs. James) (Box 19)
    - Hein, John (Box 19)
    - Henderson, Archibald, Jr. (Box 19)
    - Hendin, Herbert (Box 19)
    - Hendin, Josephine (Box 19)
    - Henry, Jules (Box 20)
    - Hertzberg, Arthur (Box 20)
    - Highet, Gilbert (Box 20)
    - Hirsch, Jerry (Box 20)
    - Hoagland, Hudson (Box 20)
    - Hoffman, Daniel G. (Box 20)
    - Hoffman, Jill (Box 20)
    - Hoffman, Theodore (Box 20)
    - Hofstadter, Albert (Box 20)
    - Hofstedter, Richard (Box 20)
    - Holland, Richard (Box 20)
    - Hollander, Jean (Box 20)
    - Hollander, John (Box 20)
    - Hollander, Robert (Box 20)
    - Holmes, Jay (Box 20)
    - Holroyd, Michael (Box 21)
    - Howard, Richard (Box 21)
    - Hsia, C.T. (Box 21)
    - Huntington, Samuel (Box 21)
    - Hurewitz, J. C. (Box 21)
    - Hyman, Harold M. (Box 21)
    - Ignatow, David (Box 21)
    - Illo, John (Box 21)
    - Ingle, Dwight J. (Box 21)
    - Issawi, Charles (Box 21)
    - Jacobs, Jane (Box 21)
    - Jacobson, Herbert L. (Box 22)
    - Jaffe, A.J. (Box 22)
    - Jarrell, Mary von Schrader (Box 22)
    - Johnson, Edgar (Box 22)
    - Jones, Jack (Box 22)
    - Jong, Erica (Box 22)
    - Kadushin, Charles and Richard Faust (Box 23)
    - Kadushin, Charles (Box 23)
    - Karp, Walter (Box 23)
    - Kavadlo, Abraham (Box 23)
    - Keene, Donald (Box 23)
    - Kenen, Peter (Box 23)
    - Keppel, Charles W. (Box 23)
    - Kilham, Peter and Peter H. Klopfer (Box 23)
    - Kimball, Penn (Box 23)
    - Kling, Richard (Box 23)
    - Kirk, Grayson (Box 24)
    - Klein, David (Box 24)
    - Klein, Jeffrey (Box 24)
    - Klein, Milton M. (Box 24)
    - Kleppner, Amy M. (Box 24)
    - Kline, George L. (Box 24)
    - Koch, Kenneth (Box 24)
    - Kohler, Richard (Box 24)
    - Komarovsky, Mira (Box 24)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard (Box 24)
    - Kouwenhoven, John (Box 24)
    - Kraft, Joseph (Box 24)
    - Krohn, Herbert (Box 25)
    - Kroll, Ernest (Box 25)
    - Kuhn, James W. (Box 25)
    - Kuhn, James and Ivor Berg (Box 25)
    - Kunitz, Stanely (Box 25)
    - Kuzma, Greg (Box 25)
    - Lall, Arthur (Box 26)
    - Lang, Berel (Box 26)
    - Lardas, Konstantinos (Box 26)
    - Lasch, Christopher (Box 26)
    - Lax, Robert (Box 26)
    - Lazarsfeld, Paul (Box 26)
    - Leab, Daniel J. (Box 27)
    - Lederman, Leon (Box 27)
    - Lee, Susan Previant (Box 27)
    - Lee, Susan Previant and Leonard Ross (Box 27)
    - Lee, Susan Previant and Chilton Williamson, Jr. (Box 27)
    - Lefkowitz, Jerome (Box 27)
    - Lehmkuhl, Donald (Box 27)
    - Lekachman, Robert (Box 27)
    - Lehman, David (Box 27)
    - Lellyveld, Joseph (Box 27)
    - Lennard, Henry (Box 27)
    - Leonard, Thomas C. (Box 28)
    - Lerner, Gerda (Box 28)
    - Levine, Al (Box 28)
    - Levine, Jack (Box 28)
    - Levine, Philip (Box 28)
    - Levy, Edgar (Box 28)
    - Lewis, Howard R. (Box 28)
    - Lewis, Thomas C. (Box 28)
    - Lipset, Seymour Martin (Box 28-29)
    - Logsdon, R. (Box 29)
    - Lomax, Alan (Box 29)
    - London, Perry (Box 29)
    - Lottman, Herbert (Box 29-30)
    - Louis, Arthur M. (Box 30)
    - Lowenthal, David (Box 30)
    - Lubell, Samuel (Box 30)
    - Lusky, Louis (Box 30)
    - Lynd, Staughton (Box 31)
    - McCarthy, Terrence (Box 31)
    - McClintock, Robert (Box 31)
    - McCormick, Jeri (Box 31)
    - McDonald, Ellen E. (Box 31)
    - McGill, William J. (Box 31)
    - McNeal, Robert H. (Box 31)
    - MacDonald, Dwight (Box 31)
    - MacInnes, Colin (Box 31)
    - MacShane, Frank (Box 31)
    - Mandel, Oscar (Box 32)
    - Mann, Erica see Jong, Erica (Box 32)
    - Marcus, Steven (Box 32)
    - Martin, William McChesney, Jr. (Box 32)
    - Margulies, Martin (Box 32)
    - Martinetti, Ronald A. (Box 32)
    - Mathews, Jackson (Box 32)
    - Mathewson, Rufus (Box 32)
    - Mathewson, Ruth (Box 32)
    - Mattison, Alice (Box 32)
    - Mayer, Kurt B. (Box 32)
    - Mayer, Jean (Box 32)
    - Mazlish, Bruce (Box 33)
    - Mazzeo, Joseph (Box 33)
    - Mead, Margaret (Box 33)
    - Mead - Byers Conference (Box 33)
    - Mellow, James R. (Box 33)
    - Melman, Seymour (Box 33)
    - Merton, Robert K. (Box 33)
    - Metzger Walter P. (Box 34)
    - Merwin, W.S. (Box 34)
    - Meyer, Bernard C. (Box 34)
    - Middle East — Exchange (Box 34)
    - Milner, Lucille B. (Box 34)
    - Milner, Murray (Box 34)
    - Mintz, Sidney (Box 34)
    - Moers, Ellen (Mrs. Martin Mayer) (Box 34)
    - Moley, Raymond (Box 35)
    - Moore, Douglas (Box 35)
    - Morgan, Frederick (Box 35)
    - Morris, Ivan (Box 35)
    - Morton, Henry W. (Box 35)
    - Moss, Howard (Box 35)
    - Motz, Lloyd (Box 35)
    - Murray, Philip (Box 35)
    - Navasky, Victor (Box 35)
    - Neely, James C. (Box 36)
    - Niebuhr, Reinhold (Box 36)
    - Niflis, Michael (Box 36)
    - Nisbet, Robert A. (Box 36)
    - Nitchie, George W. (Box 36)
    - Nordsiek, W. (Box 36)
    - O'Brien, Conor Cruise (Box 36)
    - O'Brien, Justin (Box 36)
    - 0'Gorman, Ned (Box 36)
    - O'Neill, Lawrence H. (Box 37)
    - Ostow, Mortimer (Box 37)
    - Pack, Robert (Box 37)
    - Packard, Edward B., Jr. (Box 37)
    - Padgett, Ron (Box 37)
    - Palfrey, John G. (Box 37)
    - Papanderou, Andreas (Box 37)
    - Papke, David R. (Box 37)
    - Passell, Peter & Leonard Ross (Box 37)
    - Paulson, Monrad (Box 37)
    - Peffer, Nathaniel (Box 38)
    - Pei, Mario A. (Box 38)
    - Pepper, William F. (Box 38)
    - Perlman, Helen Harris (Box 38)
    - Petersen, William (Box 38)
    - Peyser, Joan (Box 38)
    - Pfaff, William (Box 38)
    - Phillips, Wayne (Box 38)
    - Piaget, Jean (Box 38)
    - Piven, Frances (Box 39)
    - Polgar and Guttmacher (Box 39)
    - Rabassa, Gregory (Box 39)
    - Rabinovitz, Rubin (Box 39)
    - Radcliffe, Jane (Box 39)
    - Raditsa, Bogdan (Box 39)
    - Rados, David L. (Box 39)
    - Randall, Francis B. (Box 39)
    - Randall, Laura (Box 39)
    - Raskin, Eugene (Box 39)
    - Reff, Theodore (Box 39)
    - Reik, Miriam (Box 39)
    - Riesman, David (Box 40)
    - Reissman, Frank (Box 40)
    - Riffaterre, Michael (Box 40)
    - Roberts, Henry L. (Box 40)
    - Rodriguez, Richard (Box 40)
    - Rogers, Katherine M. (Box 40)
    - Rosenberg, John D. (Box 40)
    - Rosten, Leo (Box 40)
    - Rothberg, Abraham (Box 40)
    - Rondiez, Leon (Box 40)
    - Rousseas, Stephen W. (Box 40)
    - Rudman, Mark (Box 40)
    - Russakow, Michael R. (Box 41)
    - Said, Edward (Box 41)
    - Sansom, George (Box 41)
    - Sarris (Box 41)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. (Box 41)
    - Schmidt, George (Box 41)
    - Schoenbrun, David F. (Box 41)
    - Schrag, Peter (Box 41)
    - Schrag, Philip (Box 41)
    - Seabury, Paul (Box 41)
    - Shapiro, Harvey (Box 42)
    - Shapiro, Samuel (Box 42)
    - Sheffer, Eugene (Box 42)
    - Sherwin, Judith Johnson (Box 42)
    - Siegel, Paul N. (Box 42)
    - Sills, Yole G. (Box 42)
    - Silver, Nathan (Box 43)
    - Simpson, Louis (Box 43)
    - Sirkin, Gerald and Natalie (Box 43)
    - Sloane, Edward J. (Box 43)
    - Slote, Michael Anthony (Box 43)
    - Snow, Edgar (Box 43)
    - Spender, Stephen (Box 43)
    - Sprinchorn, Evert (Box 43-44)
    - Stade, George (Box 44)
    - Starr, Louis M. (Box 44)
    - Steegmuller, Francis (Box 44)
    - Stein, Howard F. (Box 44)
    - Stern, Fritz (Box 44)
    - Stevens, Roger L. (Box 44)
    - Stilman, Leon (Box 44)
    - Stoloff, Carolyn (Box 44)
    - Stone, I.F. (Box 44)
    - Suther, Marshall (Box 44)
    - Sutton, Samuel (Box 44)
    - Sweeney, Siadhal (Box 44)
    - Syrett, Harold C. (Box 44)
    - Tagliabue, John (Box 45)
    - Tannenbaum, Frank (Box 45)
    - Taube, Mortimer (Box 45)
    - Tauber, Abraham (Box 45)
    - Taylor, Davidson (Box 45)
    - Taylor, John M. (Box 45)
    - Temko, Allan (Box 45)
    - Temple, Ruth (Box 45)
    - Theobald, Robert (Box 45)
    - Tong, Te-kong (Box 45)
    - Torre Bueno, Theodore de la (Box 45)
    - Tiger, Lionel / Robin Fox (Box 46)
    - Tiger, Virginia (Box 46)
    - Trilling, Lionel (Box 46)
    - Truman, Harry S. (Box 46)
    - Tucker, Martin - Soyinka (Box 46)
    - Tugwell, Rexford (Box 46)
    - Unterecker, John (Box 46)
    - Van Doren, Mark (Box 47)
    - Viederman, Steve (Box 47)
    - Villasenor, Laura Wells De (Box 47)
    - Voznesensky, Andrei (Box 47)
    - Wachtel, Paul (Box 47)
    - Wagley, Charles (Box 47)
    - Wagner, Geoffrey (Box 47)
    - Wakefield, Dan (Box 47)
    - Wald, Richard (Box 47)
    - Wallerstein, Immanuel M. (Box 47)
    - Ward, Barbara / Jackson (Box 47)
    - Ward, John William (Box 47)
    - Warren Commission Report (Box 47)
    - Wasserstrom, William (Box 48)
    - Weales, Gerald (Box 48)
    - Weidhorn, Manfred (Box 48)
    - Weiner, Leslie (Box 48)
    - Weingartner, Rudolph H. (Box 48)
    - Weinreich, Uriel (Box 48)
    - Weinstein, William (Box 48)
    - Weisman, Steven R. (Box 48)
    - Wenglinsky, Martin (Box 48)
    - Wensberg, Erik (Box 49)
    - Westin, Alan F. (Box 49)
    - Whiting, Allen (Box 49)
    - Wickes, George (Box 49)
    - Wise, David (Box 49)
    - Wishy, Bernard (Box 49)
    - Withers, Carl (Box 49)
    - Witkovitch, Carl (Box 49)
    - Wolf, Leonard (Box 49)
    - Wood, Michael (Box 49)
    - Wollon & Ericson (Box 49)
    - Wootton of Abinger, Bareness (Box 49)
    - Wrong, Dennis (Box 49)
    - Wu, Chien-shiung (Box 50)
    - Yankelovich, Daniel (Box 50)
    - Zinn, Howard (Box 50)
    - Zinner, Paul (Box 50)
    - Zweig, Paul (Box 50)
  - Artist's Morgue, Rejections, and Covering Letters
    - 1963 July 1-1965 (Box 51)
    - Art
      - Cover Art 1966 (Box 52)
      - cover colors (Box 52)
      - cover correspondence (Box 52)
      - Permissions (Box 52)
      - Robert Cato (Box 52)
      - Artists correspondence (Box 52)
      - Covers (Box 52)
      - Type (Box 52)
      - Stock (Box 52)
      - preliminary samples and estimates, etc. (Box 52)
    - Feliks Topolski (Box 52)
    - Rejections
      - 1967-1969 (Box 53)
      - 1964 (A-L)-1967 (Box 54)
      - 1964 (M-Z) (Box 55)
    - Chronological
      - No. 9 October 1, 1961-March 1962 (Box 55)
      - No. 10 March 1962 - August 1962 (Box 55)
      - No. 11 September 1962 - February 1, 1963 (Box 55)
      - No. 12 February 1, 1963 - June 30, 1963 (Box 55)
      - No. 17 April 1, 1965 - December 1966 (Box 56)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 56)
  - Series III: Organizational Materials
    - Good Intentions (Box 57)
    - Style Manual (Box 57)
    - Art Sources (Box 57)
    - Possible Contributors, waiting to hear from them (Box 57)
    - Possible Contributors — CONA (Box 57)
    - Rejections, 1970 (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous loose materials (Box 57)
- Series IV: Journal Items
  - Letters & Before the House
    - Letters used in Volume II, No. 1 (Box 58)
    - Alphabetical
      - Adkins, L. John (Box 58)
      - Athletics Symposium: possibles (Box 58)
      - Barnouw, Erik (Box 58)
      - Bendiner, Alfred (Box 58)
      - Berg, Aaron (Box 58)
      - Blaustein, Albert (Box 58)
      - Booth, Philip (Box 58)
      - Boorstin, Daniel J. (Box 58)
      - Bowles, Frank (Box 58)
      - Burns, Arthur F. (Box 58)
      - Burns, Gerald (Box 58)
      - Cane, Melville (Box 58)
      - Carter, Hodding (Box 58)
      - Clifford, James L. (Box 58)
      - Clough, Shepard B. (Box 58)
      - Davis, Robert Gorham (Box 58)
      - Day, Lincoln (Box 58)
      - Daykarhanova, Tamara (Box 58)
      - De Bary, William T. (Ted) (Box 58)
      - de Bethune, Andre J. (Box 59)
      - De Toledano, Ralph (Box 59)
      - Disarmament and Arms Control (Box 59)
      - Dobzhansky, Theodosius (Box 59)
      - Donald, David (Box 59)
      - Dupee, Fred (Box 59)
      - Fadiman, Clifton (Box 59)
      - Fairbridge, Rhodes (Box 59)
      - Fatout, Paul (Box 59)
      - Feldman, Leonard (Box 59)
      - Flanagan, Thomas (Box 59)
      - Forcey, Charles (Box 59)
      - Frankel, Charles (Box 59)
      - Freedman, Morris (Box 59)
      - Freidel, Frank (Box 59)
      - Gallo, Louis (Box 59)
      - Garwin, Richard L. (Box 59)
      - Gilmore, Louis (Box 59)
      - Ginzberg, Eli (Box 59)
      - Goodjohn, Arlouine (Box 59)
      - Graff, Henry (Box 59)
      - Grossman, Larry (Box 59)
      - Gruver, William R. (Box 59)
      - Hardwick, Elizabeth (Box 59)
      - Heffner, Richard (Box 59)
      - Herold, J.C. (Box 59)
      - Hoffman, Daniel G. (Box 59)
      - Hoffman, Theodore (Box 60)
      - Hollander, John (Box 60)
      - Hook, Lucyle (Box 60)
      - Hurewitz, Jacob (Box 60)
      - Issawi, Charles (Box 60)
      - Jackson, W.T.H. (Box 60)
      - Jaffe, Abram (Box 60)
      - Jessup, Philip (Box 60)
      - Jimeniz, Juan Ramon (Box 60)
      - Kardiner, Abram (Box 60)
      - Klein, Sidney (Box 60)
      - Kristol, Irving (Box 60)
      - Krutch, Joseph Wood (Box 60)
      - Kusch, Polykarp (Box 60)
      - Lang, Paul (Box 60)
      - Lazarus, Harold (Box 60)
      - Lesser, Alexander (Box 61)
      - Luening, Otto (Box 61)
      - Lundberg, Isabel Cary (Box 61)
      - Maccoby, Michael (Box 61)
      - MacMahon, Arthur W. (Box 61)
      - Marshall, Howard D. (Box 61)
      - Mead, Margaret (Box 61)
      - Melko, Matthew F. (Box 61)
      - Melman, Seymour (Box 61)
      - Mills, C. Wright (Box 61)
      - Montagu, Ashley (Box 61)
      - Moonshooter — distribution & comment (Box 61)
      - Muller, H.J. (Box 61)
      - Monroe, Pat (Box 61)
      - O'Connell, Donald (Box 61)
      - O'Neill, Lawrence H. (Box 61)
      - Phillips, Ellis (Box 61)
      - Pleasants, Jeanne (Box 61)
      - Podhoretz, Norman (Box 61)
      - Rabi, I.I. (Box 61)
      - Radhakrishnan (Box 62)
      - Rice, Dustin (Box 62)
      - Robertson, David (Box 62)
      - Rogers, Lindsay (Box 62)
      - Rosenhaupt, Hans (Box 62)
      - Rovere, Richard H. (Box 62)
      - Runciman, Garry (Box 62)
      - Russian Students (Box 62)
      - Sayre, Wallace (Box 62)
      - Schmidt, Dana Adams (Box 62)
      - Schulert, Arthur (Box 62)
      - Schwartz, Laszlo (Box 62)
      - Seminars (Box 62)
      - Simmons, Ernest J. (Box 62)
      - Skinner, Elliot (Box 62)
      - Steegmuller, Francis (Box 62)
      - Stein, Harold (Box 62)
    - Chronological
      - 1960-1961 (Box 63)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 64)
      - 1963-1965 (Box 65)
  - Unpublished Articles
    - Authors — ideas for (Box 66)
    - Authors' correspondence (Box 66)
    - Bitensky, Reuben (Box 66)
    - Blanchard, Jean-Marc (Box 66)
    - Braudy, Leo (Box 66)
    - Bronowski, J. (Box 66)
    - Carr, Arthur C. (Box 66)
    - Columbia Issue (Box 66)
    - Conklin (Box 66)
    - Donadio, Stephen (Box 66)
    - Dorrothy, John (Box 66)
    - Friedman, John (Box 66)
    - Garwin, R.L. (Box 66)
    - Gazarian, Marie-Lise (Box 66)
    - Ginzberg, Eli (Box 66)
    - Hall, Reid (Box 66)
    - Hendin, Herbert (Box 66)
    - Hill, Robert (Box 67)
    - Hurewitz, J. C. (Box 67)
    - Jacobs, Jane (Box 67)
    - Jammer /Arabs vs. Israelis (Box 67)
    - Jochnowitz, George (Box 67)
    - Kinzel, Augustus (Box 67)
    - Kroeber, Karl (Box 67)
    - Kostelanetz, Richard (Box 67)
    - Kuo, John T. (Box 67)
    - Kusch, Polykarp (Oona's acting editorship) (Box 67)
    - Lang, Berel (Box 67)
    - Lemle, Edna (Box 67)
    - McDonald, Laughlin (Box 67)
    - Mayer, Jean (Box 67)
    - Metraux, Daniel (Box 67)
    - Meyer, Bernard (Box 67)
    - Moore, John A. (Box 67)
    - Moss, Melvin (Box 67)
    - Mouchly, Ehud (Box 68)
    - Neuberger, Gottfried (Box 68)
    - Pell, Claiborne (Box 68)
    - Peyser, Herbert (Box 68)
    - Rosenfeld, Henry (Box 68)
    - Rosenthal, Albert (Box 68)
    - Salmen, Stanley (Box 68)
    - Schoenbrun, David (Box 68)
    - Seligman, Eustace (Box 68)
    - Shanks, Hershel (Box 68)
    - Shoup, Carl S. (Box 68)
    - Stessin, Lawrence (Box 68)
    - Temple, Ruth (Box 68)
    - Trilling, Diana (Box 68)
    - Trilling, Lionel (Box 68)
    - Wagley, Charles (Box 68)
    - Wald, George (Box 68)
    - Weingartner, Rudolph (Box 68)
    - Wolff, Robert Paul (Box 68)
    - Yevick, Miriam (Box 68)
    - Zinn, Howard (Box 68)
  - Comments
    - Vol.II, Misc. - Circulation, correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 69)
    - Circulation, 1960 (Box 70)
    - first issue (Box 70)
    - Readers, 2nd issue (Box 70)